It's a fun journey, especially if you are new if this is your second or third time around you will be continue to grow
In your skills as well. My name is Anil Thomas. I'm the head of
AI engineering and innovation here at PMA. This company was started by Dr. Nancy Lee
She's the CEO founder came up with this idea and brought together kind of a wide array of tools to bring this to fruition
The goal of this project this whole cohort is to gain
Experience in AI ML the development life cycle as well as what does an HL agile methodology look like and to really get hands-on experience
What we're gonna learn kind of throughout this whole program is it's an 11-week program
It's a project base structure with
Identifying actual user pain points. So the designers and the product manager will go out and actually
Interview potential stakeholders. It could be B to B or B to C finding out
Is it rather than just a being an idea?
How are they solving the pain point today isn't a real pain point and is this something that we can really work on?
The learning objective is to build an AI solution in the real world in a project-based setting to explore and exploit
Gen AI tools and framework and then to deliver a feature rich minimal viable based product based on predetermined success
On this journey, you'll kind of learn through technical skill development core AI ML concepts gen AI and data engineering
Project-based learning as well so agile spray methodology scrum methodology team collaborations and real-world applications
If you look at the chat that I just put some details
I'll go over that in a little bit
But that has some of the documentation in regard to some of the training both from a document perspective as well as a YouTube
Playlist for the engineers and the designers and data scientists
So I want to talk through the timelines a little bit make sure that we're all kind of on the same page
So we are starting this week
So this is considered week one from the 15 through the 21st throughout this from the designers and the engineers standpoint
There will be some training documentation that the designer should review as well as the agile methodology
For the engineers and data scientists also training in AI concepts
So looking at the documentation start reviewing the YouTube playlist as well as agile methodology understanding the framework for the engineers as well
There's gonna be an assignment from week one to three
It'll be a job tracker
Agent or a discord FAQ chatbot or it'll be a team assignment
Basically that team assignment is helping out with an existing team from a previous cohort
Which is already started the development process, but they're continuing to build
So we'll be looking based on some of your skill sets if that's an opportunity as well
Then for next week week two there'll be pitch day that'll be roughly September 16th
That's really for the product managers and the designers so the product managers next week
You will be pitching your idea to the designers and
The designers will have a team match spreadsheet that you will fill out
Kind of explaining which one of those you're interested in and then the designers and the product manager should kind of reach out to each other
via discord to kind of have a conversation which
Right which team individual would be the right match
So we are looking for right now two designers roughly to start off for each AI product team
And it would be kind of a senior designer and a junior designer for a specific AI product team
While that's happening the engineers are continuing to work on the the assignment the job tracker the discord FAQ
Or if you're allocated to a team and continuing your learning process
So one of the things for the product managers and designers
Make sure that you have a calendar invite for september 16th
If not, let marla or myself know via email or discord and we'll make sure that you have the respective calendar invite for that day
Then for the designers after the pitch day is done and you are part of a team
Now you are actually helping the product managers going through the interview process going out looking at what does the real world
How are they managing the issue currently?
What are the best ways that you know, you could potentially resolve this and you'll work through that
Also, you'll be working on a high fidelity
Layout so that week four will be the the pitch day where the product managers and the designers will be pitching to the engineers and data scientists
While that's occurring week three continuing the engineers and data scientists are continuing to work on their assignments
Then pitch day that's week four
That's the the bigger pitch day where the like I mentioned the product managers and the designers are pitching to all of the engineers
It'll be a zoom call just like this. All of these pitch days are zoom calls that are also recorded
Everyone should verify that you have a calendar invite for october 7th
And once that pitch day is done the engineers and data scientists will fill out a google form
Where you'll rank your top three AI products based on the pitch
Also, if you're willing to be a lead engineer
From your role and what you selected within your top three
I will then determine
Which one of the top three that you've chosen you'll be a part of and that's what you'll work on continuing forward
There are some product managers that have only signed up for the first four weeks
So you'll be a part of this first four-week process and then a few product managers will kind of drop off
For the others that are continuing from the building standpoint will then keep going
Now, let me talk a little bit more about what the match process looks like. So like I mentioned week two september 20